艾克森把我们扔在这里等死
Ackerson left us down there to die.
前情提要
没有撤离计划 没有战甲
No evac, no armor.
-海军情报局早就知道我们撑不下去  -城市沦陷了
ONI knew we wouldn't make it. The city fell
致远星上的事并非针对你个人 是政治需要
What happened on Reach wasn't personal, it was political.
-是巴拉戈斯基  -海军情报局一向护犊子
- It was Parangosky. - The ONI protects itself.
与他们为敌 即便你是
Make them your enemy, and it won't matter
士官长都没用
that you're Master Chief.
你什么时候脱离的海军情报局 上将
When did you leave ONI, Admiral?
拜托 能帮帮他吗
Please, will you help him?
那你可以为我做些什么呢
What are you prepared to do for me?
这个人类的东西有什么价值
知识 人类的知识
-你对恶魔了解多少  -他记得你
What do you know of the Demon? - He remembers you.
你保留了他的记忆 给我看看
You keep his memories. Show me.
你将是带领我们走向圣迹环带的人
我该怎么办？
相信我 我是世尊者
建造出光环的东西在你身上留下了印迹
Whatever built the Halo left something in you.
它很接近了 那个恶魔
It's close now, the monster.
来找我 救赎我 拯救我
Find me, deliver me, save me.
不要放弃你的名字 守护者
Do not forsake your name, Protector.
你这个是哪儿来的
Where did you get this?
一个男孩给我的
A boy gave it to me.
-他人呢  -他们把他带走了
－ Where is he? - They took him away.
-谁把凯斯勒带走了  -联合国太空指挥部
Who took Kessler? - The UNSC.
他叫瓦纳克134
His name was Vannak- 134.
我会找到致你死亡的那些人
I will find the ones who caused your death.
然后将他们了结
And I will end them.
这里曾是我的家 是我的朋友们
This was my family, my friends!
没有人训练过我怎么面对这个
There's no training for this!
我没法留下来看着
I can't stay and watch.
你是建议我在没有队长的情况下给银队布置任务吗
Are you suggesting I deploy Silver Team without its leader?
就给我 直到约翰洗清罪名
Just me, till John's cleared.
你我都清楚他已经不是他自己了
You and I both know he s not himself.
WU11 这里是凤凰号
Whiskey- uniform one- one. This is Phoenix.
保持速度
Maintain speed.
我们训练的目的就是这个
This is what we've trained for.
是时候回报他们了
It's time to pay them back.
如果你弹开那个船体 之后两小时就会
You bounce off that hull, you're gonna spend
一直在太空里转圈圈 那我就得
your last two hours spinning into space, and I'm gonna
写份报告阐述你是有多愚蠢
have to write a report about what a dumbass you are.
而我又很讨厌写报告
And I hate writing reports.
就算写也不会是写我
You ain't gonna write about me.
标枪突击队
Assault Unit Javelin,
可以跳了
you are clear for jump.
一队
First squad,
向前转
on the beam!
-斯巴达战士  -永不死
Spartans! Never die!
祝好运 斯巴达战士们
Godspeed, Spartans.
标枪二号 检查下你角度
Javelin- Two, check your angle.
保持队形
Maintain formation.
注意保持方向
Watch your linel
佩雷斯
Perez!
你他妈干嘛呢
What the hell are you doing?
-回到原位  -写你报告里吧
Get back into position. Put it in your report.
这里不止你一个人
You're not the only one out here!
这里是标枪队
This is Javelin.
遭受到星盟护卫舰的持续攻击
Taking sustained fire from the Covenant Corvette.
他们锁定我们了
They have a lock.
-他们看到我们了  -保持路线
They see usl- Maintain your lines!
跟踪炮塔数量击知
Unknown number of turrets tracking.
标枪队 保持分散
Javelin Team, maintain dispersion.
不要重叠
Don't overlapl
即将落上目标 三 二 一
On target in three, two, one.
凤凰号 这里是标枪一号
Phoenix, this is Javelin- One.
第一阶段完成
Phase One complete.
启动第二阶段
Initiating Phase Two.
小心炸弹
Fire in the hole!
让开
Movel Move!
舰桥就在这个甲板上面
The bridge is on this deck!
回击
Hit him back!
甲板上有烟 退后
Mark smoke on the deck! Stay back!
Mark smoke on the deckl Stay backl
海耶斯倒下了
Hayes is downl
六点钟方向有动静
Movement on our six!
移动位置
Moving!
现在 佩雷斯 走了
Now, Perezl Let's go!
跟我 快走 快走
Movel Movel
舰桥 向右突破
BridgelBreak rightl
Briclcyel Break rightl
快走
Movel Go!
吉尔罗伊 掩护我
Gilroyl Cover mel
我没事
I'm good.
换位置
Move it!
我找到了
I have itl
冈田倒下了
Okada's down!
快走
Go! Go!
-行动  -走了走了
Movel Go! Go!
检查角落
Check your corners.
安全
Clear.
我跟你说过 只有菜鸟才说”安全”
I told you, only rookies say"clear. "
我还跟你说滚
And I told you to kiss my- -
穆林斯
Mullins!
完成任务
Finish itl
舰队司令部 这里是标枪四号
Fleet Command, this is Javelin- Four.
是唯一一个还活着的人了
I'm the last one left.
准备刺入
Preparing to spike.
准备连接
Stand by to connect.
没完成
We don't have it!
该死
Goddamn it.
放轻松 斯巴达战士
Take it easy, Spartan.
你们都死了
You're all dead.
又一次死掉了
Again.
星盟的高级防护罩
The Covenant's advanced shielding
意味着每攻下一艘这种飞船我们就要损失掉三艘船
means that we lose three ships for every one of these.
他们的瞄准系统也很优越
Their targeting system is superior as well.
但这也是他们的弱点
But that is also their weakness.
请回放
Playback, please.
他们可以很轻易就锁定我们攻击舰
They have no problem locking onto our attack ships.
但对较小的目标锁定效果就比较差
But they're less effective against smaller targets.
也就是你们
That's you.
我能在2500米外干掉一个精英战士
I can take down an Elite at 2, 500 meters.
但我的步枪对付一群蜜蜂就毫无用处了
But my rifle is useless against a swarm of bees.
就是说我们现在就是蜜蜂
So we're bees now?
你倒是想呢
You wish.
蜜蜂会群体合作
Bees work together.
众多的身体 思想统一
Many bodies. One mind.
一个任务
One mission.
渗入飞船 把尖刺捅进去
Infiltrate the ship. Deliver the spike.
舰桥就是神经中枢
The bridge is the nerve center.
外面有保护 但内部没有
It's protected on the outside, not on the inside.
抵抗不了这个
Not from this.
我们的情报显示他们的系统
Our intel indicates that their system
很容易就被腐败
is vulnerable to override.
这个刺会传播病毒
This spike delivers a virus.
系统全面关闭
Full system shutdown.
生机全无
Lights out.
就像脑袋中了一枪一样
Like a bullet to the brain.
有什么想补充的吗 斯巴达战士
Do you have something you would like to add, Spartan?
有的
Yeah.
我想说这都是扯淡 长官
I'd like to add it's bullshit, ma'am.
我们把敌人都清除了
We cleared the enemy.
那些子弹都不知道是从哪儿冒出来的
Those rounds came out of nowhere.
模拟是随机的
The simulation is random.
战争也是
So is war.
解散
Dismissed.
嘿 嘿
Heyl Heyl
我就明说了吧
Let me be clear.
我们不是平等的
We are not equals.
我是你导师
I am your instructor.
你是对我有意见吗
Do you have a problem with me?
我对失败有意见
I have a problem with failure.
对士兵不断
I have a problem with soldiers
重复犯错有意见
that continue to repeat mistakes,
不仅危及到他们的任务
jeopardizing not only their mission
还有他们战友的性命
but the lives of their comrades.
我战友们都死了
My comrades were all dead.
是在针对我吗
Is it personal?
是因为当时我在致远星而你不在吗
Is it 'cause I was on Reach and you weren't?
一场战斗不代表你就经验丰富了
One battle doesn't make you a veteran.
只代表你运气好
Just makes you lucky.
我知道入伍可能会有什么结局
I know what I signed up for.
你是在跟我说你想死吗 斯巴达战士
Are you telling me you want to die, Spartan?
不是 长官
No, ma'am.
他们在地球上
They grew leaves like these
一个叫斯里兰卡的一个小家庭果园里
on a small family orchard in a place called Sri Lanka,
种这种茶叶
on Earth
在阳光下晒干
Dried in the sun,
然后又父亲背着走出16英里
then borne on the back of the father 16 miles.
别浪费他们的牺牲
他那棕色的双脚 那片红色的土地
His brown feet, that red earth.
在拍卖会上售出
Sold at auctjon...
然后被人扛上肩膀
then placed upon shoulders,
上了船 出了海
then upon ships, then upon seas.
包装 购买
Packaged, purchased,
倒入这个易碎的杯子里
and poured into this fragile cup,
只为了入你的唇
just for your lips.
不该如此费心的
They shouldn't have.
是不该
They didn't.
这些茶叶实际上在第四层的
These leaves were actually engineered in a lab
实验室里改造出来的
on Level Four.
为什么海军情报局会关心起泡茶的问题
And why would the ONI concern itself with making tea?
因为我让的
Because I told them to.
重点的 你喝的是茶 品的却是故事
The point is, you drink the tea, but what you taste is the story.
故事很重要 但它们也很微妙
Stories are important, but they're delicate things.
茶 就像帝国一样
Tea, like empires,
几个世纪的努力都可能因为一点点疏忽而付之东流
centuries of work can be undone by the smallest of oversights.
如果你关心致远星
If you're concerned about Reach,
那故事情节就不会改变
then the narrative remains intact.
不到一小时前 一艘飞船侵入了我们的领空
A ship penetrated our airspace less than an hour ago.
我听说驾驶这艘飞船的人
I'm told whoever piloted the vessel
对我们的防御系统有所了解
showed some familiarity with our defense network.
希望你这不是在怪我
I hope that you're not blaming me.
他们降落的地方离我们
They landed less than 15 kilometers
这里不到15公里
from where we are now.
派支队伍去
Send a team.
我有没有提过 我们一位来自阿莱利亚星的特工
Did I mention that, uh, one of our agents from Aleria
确信他看到了凯瑟琳·哈尔西
is convinced he saw Catherine Halsey
登上了一艘同样的船
boarding a ship of the same description?
如果我跟你说有多少人说看到过凯瑟琳·哈尔西
If I told you how many Catherine Halsey sightings we have- -
19小时前
Nineteen hours ago.
不可能
Impossible.
她死了
She's dead.
当然 他可能看错了
Of course, he could have been mistaken.
可以是任何人 与之同行的是个 原话是
It could be anyone traveling with, and I quote,
一个伤痕累累的男人“
A scarred man.
可能是他见过的最大只的人类
Perhaps the largest human he'd ever seen.
不可能
That's not possible.
你一直说这话
You keep saying that.
你认为他还活着 还就在这个星球上
You think that he's alive, that he's here on this planet?
我想我们很快就会知道的
I suppose we're going to find out.
《光环》
第二季 第6集
暂停模拟
Pause simulation.
-你在干什么  -我睡不着
- What are you doing? - I couldn't sleep.
你不能一直来这里
you can't keep coming here.
你不觉得有点病态了吗
I mean, don't you think it's a bit morbid?
-我在训练  -你在惩罚自己
I'm training. You're punishing yourself.
之前我们为什么不在这里
Why weren't we here?
那些我们失去的人
AlI those people we lost.
我的团队
My team.
都走了
They're all gone.
不止发生在你一个人身上
It didn't just happen to you.
没人能逃脱这种悲剧
No one escapes this kind of tragedy.
没有一个新兵能在护卫舰模拟中幸存
None of the recruits survived the Corvette simulation.
他们会活下来的
They will.
他们只是需要时间 需要准备
They just need time, preparation.
我得知道我们不是派他们去执行自杀任务
I need to know we're not sending them on a suicide mission.
你曾经要求过保证吗
Did you ever ask for a guarantee?
他有过吗
Did he?
士官长走了
Master Chief is gone.
但你正在以他的形象塑造下一代
But you are making the next generation in his image.
他们不是士官长
They're not Chief.
我不能把他们变成斯巴达战士
I can't make them Spartans.
结束模拟
End simulation.
他们就是斯巴达战士
They are Spartans.
你的任务就是让他们相信这点
And it's your job to make them believe it.
那个能还给我了吗
May I have that back?
你想要什么
What is it that you want?
她一直想要的 筹码
What she always wants. Leverage.
我知道他们把你儿子带哪里去了
I know where they took your son.
这里就是哈尔西所说的一切开始的地方
This is where Halsey says it all started.
海军情报局
ONI.
你对这地方了解多少
What do you know about this place?
瑙星
Onyx.
没有地图 没有记录
No maps. No records.
没有过去
No history.
只有传闻
Just rumors.
只有窃窃私语
Just whispers.
他们抓了凯斯勒
They've got Kessler.
那里
There.
有记起什么吗
Remind you of anything?
他们还在造斯巴达战士
They're still making Spartans.
哈尔西走了
Halsey's gonel
不重要 我们不需要她了
It doesn't matter. We don't need her.
-我知道凯斯勒在哪儿  -你快去吧
I know where Kessler is. You better get going.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
索伦 我们得行动了
Soren, we need to move.
我知道你在想什么
I can see what you're thinking.
你受伤了
You're all banged up.
也没有战甲傍身
You don't have your armor.
去找你儿子吧
Go get your son.
那边
Right therel
后退
Stand down!
这是什么
What is it?
我
I
我认识这个
I know this.
它怎么会在这里
What is it doing here?
我天
Oh, my God.
我没事
I'm okay.
你说是就是吧
If you say so.
怎么会
How are.
我们在哪儿
Where are we?
你要干什么
What are you doing?
你怎么知道那个在那里的
How'd you know that was there? -
还能用
Still works.
都过20年了 拿着
After 20 years. Take it.
你以前来过
You've been here before?
是 我以前几乎就住这里
Yes. I used to practically live here.
这里是什么地方
What is this place?
一切开始的地方
It's where it all began.
我记得你
You know, I remember you.
真是受宠若惊呢
I'm flattered.
-你毁了我最好的作品  -什么
- You ruined my best work. - What?
在认识你之前 约翰始终如一 可靠 是个斯巴达战士
Before you, John was consistent. Dependable. A Spartan.
后来他遇到了你 变得难以捉摸
Then he met you and he became unpredictable.
-抱歉了  -不必
Oh, sorry about that. Oh, don't be.
有时候引入一个新的变量
Sometimes the introduction of a new variable,
无论有多微不足道
however insignificant,
都可能成为巨大变革的催化剂
can be the catalyst for huge change.
谢谢
Thanks?
通讯好像出了问题
我一直联系不上博爱城 也联系不到舰队
你认为这个故障什么时候能解决
这不是故障 是我的命令
为什么神风烈士要求我们保持沉默呢
因为我们的认为需要这样 牧师
我们要去哪儿
也许你不知道 也许你应该咨询下你的宠物
我的命令是高等先知亲自下发的
你的耻辱也是
有人说神风烈士对先知们失去了信心
并向这个人类寻求指引
那个人类对我来说毫无意义
我很乐意用我的剑平息
这些毫无根据的含沙射影
我的剑一挥
不该由我来杀她 她属于高等先知
那等我回到博爱城 我会去征求他们的同意
也就是
很快了
牧师起疑了
你跟基石交流过了吗
You have communed with the Keystone?
当然
Of course.
我可是世尊者
I am the Blessed One.
你觉得他知道吗
Do you think he knows?
你在撒谎这事
That you're lying.
都跟你说了 我看不见
I told you, I can't see!
他们人呢
Where are they?
集中火力
Concentrate your fire.
穆林斯
Mullins!
小心
Look out!
前进
Movel
我们必须前进
We have to movel
We have to move!
不能留在这里
We can't stay here.
We canft stay here,
推进前得有人发号施令
We need numbers before we push.
我来下令
I give the ordersl
火力压制
Suppressive firel
现在 前进
Move itl Nowl
前进 前进
Movingl Moving!
佩雷斯 封锁走廊
Perez, lock that corridor down.
冈田 海耶斯 奥尔森 攻击舰桥
Okada, Hayes, Olsson, assault the bridge.
如果我们按流程攻击那个房间
We assault that room by the book,
他们会再次把我们分开
they're gonna pick us apart again.
我们要一起行动 同时
We all have to go. Same time.
我们要按战术行事
We stick to the tactics.
战术就是放屁
The tactics are bullshit!
我们必须同时强攻
We gotta assault in forcel
就像妈的蜜蜂一样 兄弟们
Like the fucking bees, man!
没错
Exactly.
很好 我们都会挂掉
Great. We're all gonna die.
如果我们往上压的人足够多
If we send enough bodies,
也许能给你争取点时间破坏系统
it might buy you some time to spike the system.
你太过分了
You're out of linel
瑞奇倒下了
Richer is down!
吉尔罗伊 上来
Gilroy, get up herel...
我们执行之前的计划 结果也会是一样的
We run the same plan, it'll end the same way.
佩雷斯 你他妈这是要千嘛去
Perez! What the hell do you think you're doing?
不惜一切代价 手雷
What it takes. Frag out!
-跟我冲  -走了
On mel Move it!
On mel Move itl
加油啊 你们可以更好的
Come on, you can do better than that.
交火 后方
Contact. Rear.
这里是标枪四号 我们已抵达舰桥
This is Javelin- Four. We've reached the bridge.
动手啊
Do it!
卧槽
Holy shit!
我们现在该怎么办
What do we do now?
离开这里
Get the hell out of here.
开始撤离
Beginning exfil.
标枪 跟我走
Javelin, on me,
佩雷斯
Perezl
还等着再拿块奖章吗
You waiting on another medal?
走了
Let's go.
星盟呢
Where's the Covenant?
他们在哪儿
Where are they?
我不会坐以待毙
I'm not waiting around to find out.
另一边见
See you on the other side.
就是这样
That's how it's donel
终于
· Finally!
就是这样
That's what I'm talking about.
-恭喜  -长官
Congratulations. - Ma'am!
那个撤退 太简单了
The exfil. It was too easy.
别翘尾巴
Don't get cocky.
不是 我不是这意思
No, that's not what I meant.
我们刺入系统后 就再没见过敌人
After we spiked the system, we had no more enemy contact.
享受胜利吧 下士
Take the win, Corporal.
士官长
Master Chief.
很高兴再次见到你
Nice to see you again.
上次我们见面
Last time we met,
你拿枪指着我的脸
you had a weapon pointed in my face.
我更喜欢这样 你呢
I prefer this, don't you?
我11个手下丧失了行动能力
Eleven of my men are incapacitated.
其中一个可能会死
One of them may die.
一般人们在战斗中受伤
Usually when people are hurt in combat,
这是因为他们没有受过良好的训练
it's'cause they're poorly trained...
或者领导不力
or poorly led.
那 到底是哪一个呢
So, which was it?
那些斯巴达战士 你的钴队朋友
With those Spartans, your Cobalt friends.
我们找到他们的时候 弹夹都还是满的
You know, when we found them, they still had full mags.
一枪都没开
Never even got a shot off.
我现在觉得斯巴达战士其实没那么可怕
I'm beginning to think Spartans aren't so scary after all.
我要见巴拉戈斯基
I want to see Parangosky.
-把他栓好了  -是 队长
Clip him in. Yes, Captain.
你可以告诉她我马上就来
You can tell her I'm coming.
嗯 好 我会照做
Yeah, right. I'lI do that.
好 开始锁定
AlI right, locking down.
是我就不会
I wouldn't.
这是一个多小时前录的
This was recorded just over an hour ago.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我本来不想给你看的 但是
I didn't want to show it to you, but...
我不知道还能做些什么
I didn't know what else to do.
他还活着
He's alive.
应该是的
Seems so, yes.
怎么活下来的
How?
我们也不是很确定
We're not exactly sure.
但恐怕最可能的解释
But I'm afraid the most likely explanation
不是你我想听的
isn't one you or I want to hear.
你还记得我问你约翰和星盟代理人
Do you remember when I asked you about John's interaction
之间的互动吗
with the Covenant agent?
你说过没有理由
You said that there was no reason
质疑士官长的忠诚
to question Master Chief s loyalty.
我得问问你是否完全诚实
I have to ask if you were being entirely truthful.
我们从圣所回来的时候
When we got back from Sanctuary...
他告诉我他看见马吉了
he told me he saw Makee.
在雾里
In the fog.
就在星盟玻璃化星球之前
Before they glassed it.
-但我不认为他是真的  -没事的 凯
But I didn't think he really- - - It's okay, Kai.
我理解
I understand.
你是个好士兵
You're a good soldier.
他毕竟是士官长
And he's the Chief.
或者说曾经是
Or was.
这一切意味着什么
What does this all mean?
从我们所能确定的来看 约翰-117似乎与
From what we can ascertain, it would seem
星盟代理人马吉
that John- 117 maintained his connection
保持着联系
to the Covenant agent known as Makee.
现在看来 他们正在合作
And it appears now that they are working together.
不 不 他们不可能
No. No, they can't.
情报显示袭击期间马吉在致远星上
Intelligence places Makee on Reach during the attack.
-不可能  -约翰从致远星逃走了
No. - John escaped from Reach.
-怎么逃走的  -我不知道
How did that happen? - I don't know.
怎么逃走的 凯 其他人都
How did that happen, Kai, when everyone else- -
-你错了  -他来了
· You're wrong! He's here now.
来了这个星球 这个机构
On this planet. In this facility.
他为什么在这里 为什么要攻击联合国太空指挥部的士兵
Why is he here? Why is he attacking UNSC soldiers?
-我不知道  -为什么
- I don't know! Why?
我不知道
I don't know!
如果你有解释的话 我很想听听
If you have an explanation, I would love to hear it.
现在 我要告诉你一件事
Now, Im going to tell you something,
此信息高度机密
and this information is highly classified.
我们知道星盟攻击维谢格拉德中继站
We know the Covenant attacked the Visegrad Relay
有一个非常明确的目的
for a very specific objective:
掩盖他们对刺刀基地的攻击
to cover their assault on Sword Base,
他们在那里夺取了一件制品
where they captured one of the Artifacts.
幸运的是 我们在星球沦陷前把
Fortunately, we were able to exfiltrate the other Artifact
另一件制品带走了
before the planet fell.
制品在哪儿
Where is it?
所有文明都学会了
AlI civilizations learned
任何物体的位置都可以
that the position of any object
根据相对于夜空中的三个点来确定
can be determined relative to three points in the night sky.
这里
Here.
我感觉到了
I feel it here.
我想这是应该最好的猜测
I suppose that's as good a guess as any.
你是在嘲笑我吗
Do you mock me?
你知道如果我找不到 我会有
You do know what will become of me
-什么  -是的
- if I can't find- - - Yes.
你认为你会有什么下场呢
And what do you suppose will become of you?
如果你用那个制品把自己
If you were to use the Artifact to project yourself
投射回光环
back to the Halo,
你就能确定它在恒星中的位置 同样的方法
you could determine its location in the stars, the same way-
我不能
I can't.
不能什么
Can't what?
找到它
Find it.
我试着在脑海中去想象
I try to go there in my mind.
我碰了制品 什么都没发生
I touch the Artifact and nothing happens.
我堕落了
I'm fallen.
我被惩罚了 我的天赋不见了
I'm being punished. My gift is gone.
也许我们应该考虑更理智的可能性
Perhaps we should consider rational possibilities.
-你现在是在嘲笑我的痛苦  -你以前见过光环
Now you mock my pain. - You've seen the Halo before.
我这里有记录
I have a record of it here
把它关掉
Turn it off.
-我觉得可能会有帮助  -我说了把它关掉
I thought it might be help- - I said turn it off.
没有他我不能去那里
I can't go there without him.
情况发生了变化
Something changed.
我不知道 我们之间的某种东西
I don't know. Something between us...
不一样了
shifted.
我现在触碰基石
I touch the Keystone now.
我想找他 却只看到一片黑暗
I look for him, all I see is the dark.
也许我能帮上忙
Perhaps I can help.
我只需要进入你飞船的传输阵列
I would just need access to your ship's transmission array.
-你觉得我是傻瓜吗  -不是
- Dσ you think me a fool? - I do not.
那就别让我信任你
Then don't ask me to trust you.
你能承受不信任我的后果吗
Can you afford not to?
你知道吗 我母亲因斯巴达战士而死
You know, Spartans are the reason my mother's dead.
-拜托 我们能跳过这部分吗  -哪部分
Please, can we skip this part? - What part?
就是我对一个来自我从未去过的
The part where I say how sorry I am
地方的从未见过的人
about some person that I've never met,
说我有多抱歉那部分
from some place that I've never been.
还有你说我说那些话
The part where you say how callous I am
是多么无情那部分
for having said that.
因为事实是
Because the truth is,
这一切正在以更大的规模上演
this is all being played out on a much larger scale.
等我们走到隧道的尽头
And when we get to the end of this tunnel,
你大概就会明白了
you might actually understand.
这东西不该在这里
This isn't meant to be here.
这不该在这里
This shouldn't be here.
-这是一堵墙  -我知道是什么
I know what it is.
但它不应该在那里
But it shouldn't be there.
整个洞穴系统都被改变了
The whole cave system has been changed.
没错
Right.
-这边走  -怎么了
This way. What is it?
一种直觉
Just a feeling.
加载CIC安全区域
Load CIC secured zones.
我们失去了瓦纳克
We lost Vannak.
里兹呢
Riz?
还活着
Alive.
但没来
But not here.
你就一个人吗
You're alone?
我是吗
Am I?
我愿意为保卫致远星付出任何代价
I would have given anything to be there on Reach.
你知道的
You know that.
但你不在
But you weren't.
-我有命令在身  -谁的命令
- I had orders. - From whom?
巴拉戈斯基吗
Parangosky?
还是艾克森
From Ackerson?
他们是罪魁祸首 凯
They're responsible, Kai.
致远星 还有瓦纳克
For Reach. For Vannak.
星盟才是罪魁祸首
The Covenant's responsible.
星盟没有带走我们的战甲
The Covenant didn't take our armor.
也不是星盟把我们丢在那里自生自灭
The Covenant didn't leave us down there to die.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我说的是把你派到这里来的人
I'm talking about the people who sent you down here.
派来找我的人 海军情报局
To me. ONI.
他们知道就要发生袭击了 他们却放任整个星球烧毁
They knew an attack was coming. They let the whole planet burn.
那是谁派你来的
Who sent you?
-什么  -是马吉吗
What? - Was it Makee?
她之前也在圣所
She was on Sanctuary.
她也在中继站 也去了舰队司令部
She was at Visegrad. She was at FLEETCOM.
-凯 - 她现在在这儿吗
Kai- Is she here now?
不管我说什么 你都不会相信我
No matter what I say, you're not gonna believe me.
我想相信你
I want to believe you.
但这是不够的
That's not enough.
相信我意味着看清他们的真面目
Believing me means seeing them for what they are.
我得把你带回去 士官长
I gotta take you in, Chief.
我是来找巴拉戈斯基的
I'm here for Parangosky.
等我找她说完 你再带我回去
You can take me in when I'm done with her.
我不能让你这么做
I can't let you do that.
我想你有命令在身
I guess you have your orders.
没错
That's right.
做士兵就是这样
That's what it means to be a soldier.
你不止是个士兵
You're more than that.
我们做队友多久了 凯
How long have we been together, Kai?
很久了
A long time.
我们之间的感情值多少
And what's that worth now?
我想还不够多
I guess not enough.
我想也是
I guess not.
结局只有一个
This only ends one way.
跟我打是没有用的
There's no use in fighting me.
别担心
Don't worry.
我不会的
I won't.
瓦纳克早就死了
Vannak died...
从哈尔西带走他的那一刻他就死了
the moment Halsey took him.
一切都结束了
Everything was decided.
他的生命在他6岁时结束了
His life ended when he was 6.
我的也是
So did mine.
你的也一样
So did yours.
我们只是不知道而已
We just didn't know it.
趴下
· Stay down! Ohh!
好样的
That's it.
不要问问题
Don't ask questions.
不要去想枪口抵着的是什么 是谁
Don't even think about what's on the other side of the gun.
做他们的斯巴达战士就好
Just be their Spartan.
我知道我是什么
I know what I am.
你现在是什么
What are you now?
斯巴达战士在哪里结束 凯
Where does the Spartan end, Kai?
你又从哪儿开始呢
And where do you begin?
都结束了 约翰
This is over, John.
和我一起长大的那个女孩呢
Where's the girl I grew up with?
别说了 求你了
Stop. Please.
动手吧
Go ahead.
我不想这样
I don't want this.
我知道
I know.
但命令就是命令
An order's an order.
动手吧
Do it.
别假装自己有选择
Don't pretend you had a choice.
对致远星的攻击是不可避免的
The attack on Reach was inevitable.
他变得越来越难以控制
And he was becoming impossible to control.
士官长不在了
Master Chief is gone.
但他的记忆 他的传奇
But his memory, his legend,
能创造出百万计的斯巴达战士
will make a million more Spartans in his place.
我们想赢正需要百万计的斯巴达战士
And a million more is what we need to win.
现在这是你的项目了
This is your program now.
你做到了
You made it.
这就是它的代价
This is what it costs.
我曾经感到怀疑
I used to feel doubt.
我曾经感到内疚
I used to feel guilt.
-我想我想知道的是  -你信教吗
And I suppose my concern- - Are you a religious man?
并不是
Not particularly, no.
那我就不用担心了
Then I wouldn't worry about it.
上将 我们收到了一则加密信号
Admiral, we're receiving an encrypted transmission.
你确定信号来源了吗
Have you identified the source?
来源未知 长官 不是联合国太空指挥部的频率
Unknown, ma'am. It's not a UNSC frequency.
我们频谱之外的数据波
Data wave outside our spectrum.
高容量 追踪源点
High volume. Tracking point of origin.
长官 我们的通讯可能被破解了
Ma'am, our communications may be compromised.
都出去
Give me the room.
-长官  -出去
Ma'am? - Get out.
士官长
Chief?
Master Chief.
你好 科塔娜
Hello, Cortana.
上将
Admiral.
你在哪里
Where are you?
-你在哪里  -我就在这
Where are you? I'm right here.
哪里
Where?
科塔娜
Cortana.
在 士官长
Yes, Master Chief?
你看起来糟透了
You don't look so good.
他们对你做了什么
What did they do to you?
我还应付的来
Nothing that I didn't sign up for.
我需要你站起来 士官长
I need you to get up, Chief.
他们走了 科塔娜
They're gone, Cortana.
他们都走了
They're all gone.
但我还在这里
But I'm here.
-是的  -我来了
Yeah. I'm here now.
可怕的事情就要发生了
Something terrible is about to happen.
你想让我怎么做
What do you want me to do about it?
你是士官长
You re the Master Chief.
不再是了
Not anymore.
星盟要去寻找光环了 士官长
The Covenant's going to find the Halo, Chief.
他们打算启用光环
They're going to use it.
你必须抢先到达那里
It is imperative that you get there first.
我现在就和他们在一起
I'm with them now.
他们就快找到了
They're almost there,
我和马吉在一块儿
I'm with Makee.
马吉
Makee.
我和他们称之为神风烈士的人在一起
I'm with the one they call the Arbiter.
就是那个杀了瓦纳克的家伙
The one who who killed Vannak.
告诉我怎么找到他
Tell me how to find him.
你必须触摸那个制品
You need to touch the Artifact,
他们连接在一起的
They're connected.
我不知道它在哪里
I don't know where it is.
所以才有我的出现
That's why you have me
科塔娜
Cortana?
我可以进入星盟的系统
I was able to gain access to the Covenant systems.
我正在传送位置数据
I'm transmitting location data now.
星盟舰队什么时候到达你所在的位置
When will the Covenant Fleet arrive at your location?
很快了
Soon.
我相信这满足了我所有的任务参数
I believe this fulfills all of my mission parameters.
确实
It does.
我想联合国太空指挥部现在
I imagine the UNSC will be able to attack
有能力攻击星盟舰队了
the Covenant Fleet now.
我想你可能会感兴趣
I thought you might be interested
我模拟这次攻击已经很多次了
I've simulated the attack many times.
即使有意外的因素
Even with the element of surprise,
-成功的几率是  -谢谢科 塔娜
the chances of success are- - - Thank you, Cortana.
你还需要我做什么吗
Will you be needing anything else from me?
没有了
No
因为我总是乐意帮忙
Because I'm always happy to be useful.
你做得很好 我们都欠你的
You've done well. We re in your debt.
我现在该做什么呢
What shall I do now?
按照协议 你应该和星盟待在一起
As agreed, you'll remain where you are with the Covenant
并向我们提供情报
and provide information to us
直到你无法行动为止
until you're no longer able to do so.
明白了吗
Is that clear?
遵命 上将
Yes, Admiral
我会不会
Will I be.
被大家铭记
remembered?
我们怎么会忘记呢
How could we forget?
木已成舟了
Nothing can be undone.
别留遗憾
Have no regret.
怎么了
－ What's wrong?
这些人是谁
Who are these people?
哈尔西 停下
Halsey, stop.
哈尔西
Halsey.
你知道自己在这里做什么吗
Do you have any idea what you're doing here?
完成你做不到的事
Finishing what you couldn't.
你把我的研究报告给了他们
You gave them my research.
你真的以为
Did you really think
自己是唯一可以拯救人类的人吗
you were the only person worthy of saving humankind?
这些人缺乏能力或专业知识
These people lack the ability or the expertise- -
你的成果对我们大家都很有价值
Yeah, your work has been very valuable to all of us.
没有你的研究 我也不可能
Without your research, I never would have been able
发现你的错误
to discover your mistake.
索伦 这是什么地方
Soren, what is this place?
塞莫皮莱
Thermopylae.
这不是
Is that...?
索伦
Soren? -
他们来了
They're coming.
-谁  -我们该走了
Who? - We should get out of here.
我不明白 凯斯勒在这里吗
I don't understand. Is Kessler here?
我不应该让你下去的
I shouldn't have sent you down there.
我看到约翰身上发生什么了
I saw what happened with John.
是我的错
It's my fault.
我负全责
Put it all on me.
标枪小队今天完成了模拟
The Javelin Team completed the sim today.
你看 我就说他们可以的
You see? I told you they would.
只是时间问题
It was just a matter of time.
他们部署穿刺手榴弹后
And after they planted the spike,
顺利地到达了撤离船
they got to the evac ship without a hitch.
-太好了  -是吗
Outstanding. - Is it?
根据我的经验
In my experience,
唯一比登上星盟飞船更难的事
the only thing harder than getting on a Covenant ship
就是离开星盟飞船
is getting off of one.
是你操纵模拟了吗
Did you manipulate the simulation?
模拟效果很好 你的斯巴达战士们也一样
The simulation performed perfectly, as did your Spartans.
你故意让他们赢的
You let them win.
凯 模拟并不能反映现实
Kai, this simulation doesn't reflect reality.
只是为了训练士兵
It conditions soldiers.
我把模拟设计得很困难
I designed it to be difficult.
是为了我们的新兵逼到他们的极限
To push our recruits to their absolute limit.
在那一刻
And at that moment,
死亡似乎是等待他们的
when death seems like the only outcome,
唯一结局
to reward them.
应该给他们希望
To give them hope.
现在你想知道你的斯巴达战士是否有机会逃走
Now you want to know if your Spartans have a chance.
我告诉你 他们确实有机会
And I am telling you that they do.
但前提是他们有信念
But only if they have belief.
这就是你给他们的信念
And that is what you have given them.
你应该感到骄傲
You should be proud.
那你给了致远星上的人什么
And what did you give the people on Reach?
你在
What are you- -
启动模拟142- A 防御舰队指挥部
Initiate simulation 142- A, FLEETCOM defense.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
约翰说你把他留在这里等死
John said that you left him here for dead.
连战甲都没有
Without his armor.
你也看到了 他对那些士兵做了什么
You saw what he did to those soldiers.
-你不能相信他  -但我相信了
You can't trust him. - But I do.
我一直都相信
I always have.
他说你知道星盟要来
He said that you knew the Covenant were coming.
你让整个星球陷入火海
That you let the whole planet burn.
致远星上发生的事是场悲剧
What happened on Reach was tragic.
但也不可避免
And inevitable.
有时候 有些事情是我们无法控制的
Sometimes events are beyond our control.
在那些时刻
And in those moments...
我们能做到的
it's all we can do.
只有去拯救还有救的人
to save what we can.
就像我救了你一样
As I saved you.
模拟结束
End simulation.
你太迟了
You're too late.
我派了黑色行动组去完成你的
I've sent in the Black Ops to finish what you
你不能待在这里
You can't be in herel
站住
Stop!
嘿 你 站住 最后警告
Hey, you! Stop! Last warning!
这里是一号研究室 地下四层有入侵者
This is Research One, we have an intruder in Sublevel 4.
重复 地下四层有入侵者
Repeat, intruder in Sublevel 4.
你是怎么做到的
How are you doing this?
我有很多能力 你忘了吗
I have a lot of capabilities. Did you forget?
不 我记得
No, I remember.
你能打开这道门吗
Are you gonna get that?
科塔娜
Cortana?
这是什么意思
你的宠物说自己一无所知
这是对你的侮辱
住嘴 牧师
就在不久前 船上发出了一个信号
我真的不知道
也许你对此有所了解
传出的信号来自于这个人类的装置
我们追踪信号到了人类的行星
我不知道 天可怜见 我永远不会背叛你
做你该做的事
杀这种生物没什么荣誉
就不需要什么仪式了
你背负的耻辱已经够多了
你们当中那些真正的信徒
你们应和我站在一起
剩下的都去死吧